Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/garimawadhera-aa598010 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Usability Design
People Management
Customer Focused Design

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Limited Working)
Sanskrit (Elementary)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Durichi (Durfassianal Mark

Punjabi (Professional Working)

Certifications

Generative AI for Business Leaders Cyber Security

Designing Growth Strategies

How to Research and Write Using
Generative AI Tools

German Language Certificate Program

Honors-Awards

Instant Award for Team

Garima Wadhera

Principal Product Manager @ New Relic | Driving Product Strategy and Growth

New York, New York, United States

Summary

Data and user experience driven product geek with a passion for disruptive technologies and human-centric design. Background in startups, B2B SaaS, productivity tools.

Products built

- Backup & Restore OneDrive & SharePoint
- MSLists Mobile App
- New Relic Workflows & Automation
- UP42 B2B AI platform

Experience

New Relic
Principal Product Manager
June 2024 - Present (7 months)
New York City Metropolitan Area

Microsoft

Principal Product Manager May 2021 - June 2024 (3 years 2 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

- Lead, coach and guide the work of a team of talented product managers leading cross-functional teams across engineering, UX, sales/marketing and customer success with a product vision and strategy delivering on company mission. Regularly present strategy and results to executive leaders in monthly product reviews, quarterly strategy reviews and company all hands.
- Hold accountability for top line metrics across engagement (DAU, MAU, searches), top of funnel (new users, 30/60/90-day retention, booking adoption) as well as revenue (up-sell/cross-sell program conversions) for key core product areas.

UP42 Senior Product Manager

2019 - May 2021 (2 years)

Berlin Area, Germany

- Led the successful launch of UP42 MVP that drove x% incremental workflows, xx points improvement in NPS scores and xx% increase in paid users significantly simplifying product onboarding experience.

HUMANOO

Product Manager
September 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 1 month)
Berlin, Germany

homify Product N

Product Manager 2017 - 2017 (less than a year)

Berlin Area, Germany

localization and translation of the mobile applications/website managing the backlog of the mobile app- using the platform JIRA and Confluence

write user stories and communicate with various stakeholders like Sales, Content and SEO Team

Work in Agile environment

Publishing mobile applications in Play Store, Apple Store

Direct Reporting to the CEO

TradebooX

Software Architect and Business Analyst January 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 8 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Architect the overall end-to-end mobility platform for B2B ecosystem. Responsible for analysis, design requirements SRS, client interaction, and the overall technical plan for the application. Looked after the performance tuning, code optimization, improved application caching process, coded for back-end system as well as front-end.

Applications used- Meteor, Python, Javascript, Android, Mongo DB

My Responsibilities

-Took full ownership of our SDK and toolchain, taking care of the whole product life-cycle, from ideation to roll-out

- -Gathered requirements from relevant stakeholders and developed the product roadmap
- Analyzed the business potential of new features and prioritize them
- Designed and updated the API together with our engineers, according to evolving best practices
- -Developed the toolset around SDK, to ensure an easy and smooth integration
- Collaborated very closely with our Engineering, Solutions, Business,
 Marketing and Documentation teams through all phases of product development
- Drove product launch efforts across teams, incl. preparation of documentation, sample code, case studies, training material, etc.

Hughes Systique Corporation (HSC) Software Engineer May 2009 - 2013 (4 years) Gurgoan

Working on the Android Application.implemented Patch Utility Ancillary Protocol over three version of Android i.e 1.6 (donut), 2.1(eclair) and 2.2(froyo), Android Video Client over VoIP which uses fmmpeg x263 and x264 codecs, 3gpp and 3gpp2 protocol for SMS over VoIP.

Job Responsibilities

- clarifying requirements from clients and from managers
- estimation of projects and separate features
- development of mobile architecture
- investigation of new technology and best solution for client's projects
- android development
- providing advices for UX/UI designers about best practices in Android UX
- code review
- presentation of products, or iterative part of product to client side
- client communication
- collaboration with other(internal and client) developers teams
- integration to 3rd party providers
- create documentation for some tasks and features
- development of prototypes for clients

Tata Communications

Trainee

April 2007 - August 2007 (5 months)

Technologies - Java, C++,Perl

VSNL Internet Services Ltd. IT Consultant May 2005 - July 2005 (3 months) SDH Technologies,CDMA

Education

Panjab University
BE, ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION · (2004 - 2008)

Goethe-Institut
German A2, German Language and Literature · (2016 - 2016)

St. Thomas Senior Secondary School, Mandir Marg, New Delhi Science Stream · (1990 - 2004)